RITU PANDE

Apartment 303 24456 Conifer Farmington Hills, MI, 48335 United States Email: <u>ritz.pande@gmail.com</u>

Mobile: +1-248-756-9513

Profile

Technology principal, specializing in applied cryptography, public key infrastructure and security architecture for connected embedded devices. Experience in technically building and grooming large teams to take a product/service from conceptualization/pre-sales to deployment.

I am also an independent researcher, collaborating with experts in academia, to publish research in area of machine learning applied to biology/medicine.

Research Experience

- Publications
 - Hierarchical Neural Cellular Automata,

R Pande, D Grattarola Artificial Life Conference (ALife 2023) | Paper, Code, Talk

- Projects
 - Adaptive Traffic Signal Control using Deep Reinforcement Learning. Code
- Skills
 - Tensor Flow, Numpy, Python, Object Oriented Programming
 - Self-organizing systems, Neural Cellular Automata, Deep Learning, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Graph Neural Networks
- MOOCs
 - <u>Coursera: Natural Language Processing Specialization</u>
 - Coursera: AI for Medicine
 - Coursera: Mathematics for Machine Learning
 - Coursera: Deep Learning Specialization
 - <u>Coursera: Reinforcement Learning Specialization</u>

Professional Experience:

Employment

Company	Designation	Duration
General Motors	Software Architect, Technology Lead	Oct 2021 – Till date
Capgemini Group/ Altran Group/ Aricent Technologies/ Hughes Software Systems	 Director Technology Principal Systems Engineer Senior Technical Lead Technical Lead Senior Software Engineer 	July 2004 - Oct 2021
Wipro Technologies	Software Engineer	Oct 2002-July 2004
Innodata Information		
Technologies	System Engineer	Aug 2001 - Sept-2002

- Recent Projects
 - General Motors connected car infotainment.
 - NSN Femto Access Point
 - NSN Flexi-Edge BTS

- Skills
 - Security Architecture for embedded devices, Applied Cryptography, Public Key Infrastructure, Platform Security, Transport Layer Security, Android Security, Trusted Execution Environment, Secure Programming, Secured Onboard Communication.
 - Automotive Network Architecture, Vehicle Power Management, L2/L3 Switching

Leadership Experience:

- Experience in leading technical task force across multiple tier-1 suppliers and OEM teams to bring product features to fruition from their concept inception to deployment.
- Extensive experience in technically building and grooming large teams (largest team size being 45) in the area of IP transport, security and layer 2 switching and routing strategies.
- Deft at providing technical leadership across parallel projects, resolving interface issues across multiple subsystems.

Teaching Experience:

- Aricent Technologies: Organizational trainer for 'Debugging Skills'.
- General Motors: Organizational trainer for 'Security and Applied Cryptography Fundamentals'.

Educational Qualifications:

Bachelor of Information Tech. (1997-2001) Indraprastha College, Delhi University, India.

Awards and Achievements:

- 1 Certificate of Merit in National Mathematics Olympiad competition, 1995
- 2 Individual Employee Excellence award, Altran Group, 2008

Extra-Curricular Achievements:

- 1. 1st Degree Black Belt holder in ITF Tae-kwon-do
- 2. 1 Gold and 1 Silver in South Asian Tae-kwon-do Championships (ITF), Dec 2008
- 3 2 Gold and 1 Silver in National Tae-kwon-do Championships, Dec 2006
- 4 Completed Airtel Delhi Half Marathon '09 and '10

I hereby agree that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Ritu Pande